Palestine
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Palestine
2.1.2.1.2
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1338
- Palestine, 2.1.2.1.2
  - Lowell Thomas and servant sitting in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground [similar to 2-3 and 2-3A], 1918; 17; 2-3B; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Explosive shells, Kantara, 1918; 18; 2-9; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Baby camel and Arab, 1918; 19; 2-14; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Major seated on kneeling camel at hospital, 1918; 20; 2-19; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - View from airplane of sand dunes in the Sinai Desert (aerial view), 1918; 21; 2-24; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - View from airplane of sand dunes in the Sinai Desert (aerial view), 1918; 22; 2-24; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - View from airplane of Jaffa, looking through airplane’s guy wires (aerial view), 1918; 23; 2-39; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Lowell Thomas and military officer examining a Turkish skull in abandoned trench, 1918; 24; 2-42; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Lowell Thomas (with back to camera) and military officer at Abraham’s Well, 1918; 25; 2-45; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Lowell Thomas with British and Indian soldiers at a Turkish munitions storage area, 1918; 26; 2-47; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Lowell Thomas with British and Indian soldiers at a Turkish munitions storage area, 1918; 27; 2-47; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Lowell Thomas with British and Indian soldiers at a Turkish munitions storage area, 1918; 28; 2-47; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Hindu officer on camel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A racing dromedary from India], 1918; 29; 2-48; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Hindu officer on camel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A racing dromedary from India], 1918; 30; 2-48; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Wrecked railroad bridge, Lowell Thomas (with back to camera) and military officers in foreground, 1918; 31; 2-49; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Wrecked railroad bridge, Lowell Thomas (with back to camera) and military officers in foreground, 1918; 32; 2-49; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - View of Hebron from cemetery, 1918; 33; 2-50; 3x4 b&w (Box 1338)
  - Several people sit alongside pool at Hebron, 1918; 34; 2-51; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Abraham’s Oak, man standing in foreground, 1918; 35; 2-52; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  - Abraham’s Oak, man standing in foreground, 1918; 36; 2-52; 3x4 color (Box 1338)
  Box 1339
- Palestine, 2.1.2.1.2
  - Abraham’s Oak, man standing in foreground, 1918; 1; 2-52; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Nile water well at Khan Yunis, 1918; 2; 2-53; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Mount Pisgah where Moses saw the Promised Land, Lowell Thomas and military officer looking off into the distance, 1918; 3; 2-56; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Main street of Gaza in ruins, men on horseback in center of street, 1918; 4; 2-61; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Hole in dome of mosque at Gaza, two men on horseback in road, 1918; 5; 2-65; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Camel hospital from distance, 1918; 6; 2-67; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Army tents at sunset, 1918; 7; 2-84; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Distant view of General Edmund Allenby’s headquarters, 1918; 8; 2-86; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Jewish children, 1918; 9; 2-92; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Australian soldier with young Jewish girl, 1918; 10; 2-93; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Australian soldier with young Jewish girl, 1918; 11; 2-93; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Richon, 1918; 12; 2-95; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Richon woman, 1918; 13; 2-96; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Richon woman, 1918; 14; 2-96; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Richon woman, 1918; 15; 2-96; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Piles of oranges, many people milling about, Jaffa, 1918; 16; 2-97; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Four Scottish soldiers reading a church notice, Jaffa, 1918; 17; 2-98; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Two Scottish soldiers looking across Auja River, 1918; 18; 2-102; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Auja River crossing, 1918; 19; 2-103; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Mayor Sachs [Sacks?] [Saxe?] of Racobeth, 1918; 20; 2-106; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Mayor Sachs [Sacks?] [Saxe?] of Racobeth, 1918; 21; 2-106; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Two Australians standing on Mughar Hill, 1918; 22; 2-109; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Automobile passing through Judean Hills, 1918; 23; 2-113; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Automobile passing through Judean Hills, 1918; 24; 2-113; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Automobile on road to village near Jerusalem, 1918; 25; 2-116; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Automobile on road to village near Jerusalem, 1918; 26; 2-116; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - James McBey, official artist for the Egyptian Expeditionary Force (E.E.F.), sketching Mosque of Omar, 1918; 27; 2-120; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Bedouin hospital, 1918; 28; 2-123; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Mosque of Omar, sunset, 1918; 29; 2-124; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Patrol of Ford automobiles in desert (Lowell Thomas note: This goes with Arabian negatives), 1918; 30; 2-133; 3x4 color (Box 1339)
  - Golden Gate, 1918; 31; 2-135; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Lowell Thomas reading under tree on Mount of Olives, panorama of Jerusalem in background, 1918; 32; 2-141; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Stiftung from distance, 1918; 33; 2-151; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Siftung, close-up, three British soldiers and a child, 1918; 34; 2-152; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Bronze statue of Kaiser Wilhelm II as crusader, 1918; 35; 2-156; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  - Stiftung ceiling, mosaic of Kaiser Wilhelm II and Kaiserin Victoria, 1918; 36; 2-158; 3x4 b&w (Box 1339)
  Box 1340
- Palestine, 2.1.2.1.2
  - Mosaic of King David, 1918; 1; 2-159; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Lowell Thomas, Lieutenant General Philip Chetwode (with cane), and other British officers on the Mount of Olives [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Sir Philip Chetwode pointing toward Jericho and describing the campaign to Lowell Thomas], 1918; 2; 2-162; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Philip Chetwode and staff, Jordan Valley in background, 1918; 3; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Mosaic of Christ on throne, 1918; 4; 2-166; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Lowell Thomas with starving child, 1918; 5; 2-167; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Six beggar children sitting on street in Jerusalem, 1918; 6; 2-174; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Beggar child, rag around head, 1918; 7; 2-175; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Bishop and many beggar children, 1918; 8; 2-176; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Heavily veiled woman, 1918; 9; 2-178; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Bertha Vester and many women from Russia and Armenia stand on a balcony, 1918; 10; 2-182; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Bertha Vester and many women from Russia and Armenia stand on a balcony, 1918; 11; 2-182; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Bertha Vester and many women from Russia and Armenia stand on a balcony, 1918; 12; 2-182; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Bertha Vester with women and children, 1918; 13; 2-183; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Bertha Vester with women and children, 1918; 14; 2-183; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Proclamation (part 2), 1918; 15; 2-189; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - French Poilus guarding Holy Sepulchre, 1918; 16; 2-193; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - French Poilus guarding Holy Sepulchre, 1918; 17; 2-193; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - British staff automobiles at Jaffa Gate, 1918; 18; 2-203; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Soldiers at Lazarus’s tomb, 1918; 19; 2-207; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Vale of Adjalon, 1918; 20; 2-208; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Good Samaritan Inn, two tents and soldiers at right, 1918; 21; 2-209; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Colonel Camp and three British officers, 1918; 22; 2-210; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Group of officers in front of office of military governor of Bethlehem, 1918; 23; 2-211; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - French Poilus and British soldiers on guard at Church of Nativity in Bethlehem, 1918; 24; 2-213; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - Duke of Connaught, close-up, 1918; 25; 2-218; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Duke of Connaught presenting medals, distant view, 1918; 26; 2-220; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - Duke of Connaught presenting medals, distant view, 1918; 27; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 28; 2-230; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby and staff [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Allenby, the Commander in Chief; with the Duke of Connaught, uncle of the King - on left - who had been sent out to give decorations], 1918; 29; 2-231; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 30; 2-232; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 31; 2-232; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 32; 2-233; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 33; 2-233; 3x4 b&w (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby on horseback, 1918; 34; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby, profile view, 1918; 35; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  - General Edmund Allenby and wife, Mabel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lord and Lady Allenby], 1918; 36; 2-234; 3x4 color (Box 1340)
  Box 1341
- Palestine, 2.1.2.1.2
  - General Edmund Allenby and wife, Mabel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lord and Lady Allenby], 1918; 1; 2-234; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant General Philip Chetwode describing the Fall of Jerusalem to group of dignitaries, Duke of Connaught in cap [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lieutenant General Sir Philip Chetwode, Allenby’s second in command, pointing across the Dead Sea toward Arabia. Next to him, Lieutenant General Sir Harry Chevel, Australian general in command of the Anzac mountain division; Lieutenant General Sir Edwin Bulfin, Major General Sir john Shea, whose troops captured Jerusalem. The Duke of Connaught, wearing cap; the Anglican Bishop of Jerusalem and Allenby, the Commander-in-Chief.], 1918; 2; 2-236; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant General Philip Chetwode describing the Fall of Jerusalem to group of dignitaries, Duke of Connaught in cap [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lieutenant General Sir Philip Chetwode, Allenby’s second in command, pointing across the Dead Sea toward Arabia. Next to him, Lieutenant General Sir Harry Chevel, Australian general in command of the Anzac mountain division; Lieutenant General Sir Edwin Bulfin, Major General Sir john Shea, whose troops captured Jerusalem. The Duke of Connaught, wearing cap; the Anglican Bishop of Jerusalem and Allenby, the Commander-in-Chief.], 1918; 3; 2-236; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - British soldiers sitting in front of cave, 1918; 4; 2-242; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Brigadier General “Fighting Charlie” Cox approaching Jerusalem in his staff automobile, 1918; 5; 2-248; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Scottish sentry, 1918; 6; 2-263; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 7; 2-267; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 8; 2-267; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 9; 2-267; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 10; 2-267; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 11; 2-267; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Major on tall camel, commander of hospital, 1918; 12; 2-268; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Major on tall camel, commander of hospital, 1918; 13; 2-268; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - “V. C.” Smith, commander of Australian Camel Corps, 1918; 14; 2-269; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Tablet on Dog River that refers to the XXI British Army Corps, 1918; 15; 2-271; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - General Edmund Allenby and officers before carved tablet on Dog River, 1918; 16; 2-272; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Scottish soldier with mumps, 1918; 17; 2-273; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Lowell Thomas and Mayor Sachs [Sacks?][Saxe?] of Racobeth, 1918; 18; 2-279; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Little boy saluting wearing oversize military hat [Malta], 1918; 19; 2-300; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Woman with hay on head, 1918; 20; 2-343; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Woman with hay on head, 1918; 21; 2-343; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Colonel Camp, 1918; 22; 2-350; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - General Ronald Storrs, 1918; 23; 2-352; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - British soldier on guard at Mount of Olives, large tree in foreground, 1918; 24; 2-355; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Jerusalem panorama with olive grove in foreground, 1918; 25; 2-356; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Jerusalem panorama with olive grove in foreground, guide and British soldier on wall, 1918; 26; 2-361; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Garden of Gethsemane, 1918; 27; 2-369; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Stiftung from Russian Spire, 1918; 28; 2-371; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Stiftung Tower from roadway, many trees in foreground, 1918; 29; 2-376; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Woman drinking tea (Lowell Thomas note: Gray hair to look as aged as possible), 1918; 30; 2-388; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Woman drinking tea (Lowell Thomas note: Gray hair to look as aged as possible), 1918; 31; 2-388; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Panorama of Jerusalem, 1918; 32; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Mosque of Omar, 1918; 33; 3x4 b&w (Box 1341)
  - Rock formation on the Dead Sea [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Lot’s Wife” near the southern end of the Dead Sea], 1918; 34; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Rock formation on the Dead Sea [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Lot’s Wife” near the southern end of the Dead Sea], 1918; 35; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  - Rock formation on the Dead Sea [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Lot’s Wife” near the southern end of the Dead Sea], 1918; 36; 3x4 color (Box 1341)
  Box 1342
- Palestine, 2.1.2.1.2
  - Rock formation on the Dead Sea [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Lot’s Wife” near the southern end of the Dead Sea], 1918; 1; 3x4 b&w (Box 1342)
  - Rock formation on the Dead Sea [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Lot’s Wife” near the southern end of the Dead Sea], 1918; 2; 3x4 b&w (Box 1342)
  - Man holding an umbrella reads a book as he floats on his back in the Dead Sea, 1918; 3; 3x4 color (Box 1342)
  - Man holding an umbrella reads a book as he floats on his back in the Dead Sea, 1918; 4; 3x4 b&w (Box 1342)
  - Man holding an umbrella reads a book as he floats on his back in the Dead Sea, 1918; 5; 3x4 b&w (Box 1342)